Mahmoud Bashir

Android Developer

I'm an Android Developer with over 2 years of experience, I have studied computer science at university, I gain a lot of experience in many topics like Data structure, Algorithm, system analysis and design, networking, cloud computing, and many other topics , I keep my skills updated and learn modern technologies , Highly adaptable to technical changes. I have an experience in working as freelancer.

I have an experience in working with in-built printer handheld pos (ex. SUNMI-V2 PRO) for printing and scanning.



Address

Cairo

Nasr - City

Phone +201558440959

Whatsapp

+201096589671

E-mail

mahmoudbashir830@gmail.com

Date of birth 1997-02-03

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahmou

d-bashir-070553146/

GitHub

https://github.com/MahmoudBashir97



Skills

Software

Android Studio

NetBeans & Zeplin & Slack

Postman Visual studio & Vs

Code

Languages

Arabic

English



Conferences

2016-03

Maker Faire Cairo

2018-09

Egypt Engineering Day(EED)



Interests

Sports

Music

Reading

Experience

2020-09 -**Android Developer** 2020-12

Saudi Blockchain 2022-11 -

Android Developer 2021-01 Khidmitty

2021-02 -**Android Developer** present Electric Power Systems Engineering Co. (EPS)

Education

2015-09 -**Zagazig University** 2019-07

• Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

IT Department

· GPA (Very Good)

Projects

Cova delivery app (Freelance)

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.mahmoud.bashir.cova_app

- Cova Delivery app for delivering coffee that requested from users.
- Connected with backend created in php framework.
- Depends on Map for reach to shop and deliver order to destination customer.
- · Uses Google Map Api Platfrom (directions & routes, places).
- · Uses Push Notification For notifying a new coming orders.

(Freelancer) حجز کورة

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?

id=com.besheer.mahmoud.l3b koora

- · Its For booking a football small stadium for playing football with friends or others.
- Uses Map for finding a near stadiums.
- Uses Firebase Realtime for getting stadiums data and sending booking info.
- · Uses FCM Push Notification For getting a notify if there is an offers or news from the dashboard.
- Soon will add a payment method and make it work in real.

O Food (Freelancer)

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?

id=com.mahmoud.bashir.ofood

- O Food is an ordering food app, with some kinds of countries special food, cuisine.
- · Uses Firebase Realtime for getting food data and setting an orders info .
- Uses FCM Push Notification For getting a notify if there is an offers or news from the dashboard.
- Simple UI design , with a UI of Payment method .

Chat Ho! (Freelancer)

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.chatho.chatho

- Chat Ho! is a simple chatting app with anyone who using it.
- Uses Firebase Realtime for chatting, new friends, stories, creating and chatting groups .
- Uses Firebase Authentication with Mobile Number and Email for signing up.
- Uses FCM Push Notification for notifying a new coming message and new friend requests.

News app (pushed on GitHub)

https://github.com/MahmoudBashir97/News_App

- Simple app for getting a news data from Third part library (Restful api).
- Developed with Kotlin language for android development.
- Uses this Technologies: MVVM, Coroutines, Room, Navigation Component, Pagination.

Movies app(pushed on GitHub)

- https://github.com/MahmoudBashir97/Movies-App Simple app for getting a news data from Third part library (Restful api).
- · Developed with Kotlin language for android development .
- Uses this Technologies: MVVM, Coroutines, Room, Navigation Component, Pagination.

(يوميات مسلم (أذكار - القرآن الكريم-مواقيت الصلاة Muslim Daily

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?

id=com.mahmoudbashir.azan_app

- · It's a simple app for providing muslims with Pray times, Azkar, provide a
- Developed with Kotlin language for android development.
- Uses this Technologies : MVVM , Repository pattern , Room , Navigation
- Component , Alarm Manager , Coroutines , Broadcast receiver. · Uses Alarm manager for alarming azan time, with notification.
- Getting user location at first time, for getting pray time data from api.

(Freelancer) منتاليتي Mentality

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?

id=com.mahmoud.bashir.enneagramblaraby

- It's a simple app for personality testing ,that gives a static questions , then view a result that depends on your answers.
- Developed with Java language for android development.
- Simple UI design with a nice Characters that describe your personality.

This online resume is GDPR compliant. The user can unpublish it at any time.

CV **Cover Letter** Resume Resume Builder CV Builder Cover Letter Builder **Cover Letter Templates** Resume Templates CV Templates Resume Examples Cover Letter Examples CV Examples Resume Format **CV** Format Cover Letter Format How to Write a Resume How to Write a CV How to Write a Cover Letter Resume Help CV Help Cover Letter Help Best Resume Templates Free Cover Letter Templates

Support Languages English (AU) About Contact English (IE) Privacy Policy English (NZ)

Free Resume Templates

Español Français (Canada) Français (France) Terms of service English (UK) Italiano English (US) Português